PAMELA OLNEY

pamela.olney@yahoo.com | https://pamelaolney.github.io/

SUMMARY

A Full Stack Web Developer that uses logic oriented principles and harnesses proven methodologies to help organizations investigate complex issues, identify and solve problems, improve processes and increase efficiency and efficacy. Utilizes assorted work experiences to create an array of solutions.

SKILLS

- HTML/CSS
- **JavaScript**
- *j*Query
- AngularJS
- NodeJS
- MongoDB
- Ruby on Rails
- Bootstrap

- Active Record
- ERP SAP Business One
- Business and Marketing Development

June 2016 – September 2016

- Analytics Training
- Inventory level management
- MEAN Stack

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Washington, DC

Web Development Immersive Student

General Assembly's Web Development Immersive program is an intense 12-week course that goes through a variety of frameworks, programming languages, libraries etc. We have completed a variety of projects to display our knowledge and understanding of what we have learned such as building full-stack RESTful web applications using object-oriented programming while utilizing multi-relational databases.

Project - Makali: A full stack Ruby Rails Application utilizing RESTful routes with full CRUD functionality. Uses embedded ruby html pages for views. Also it is crafted in a way that users are only able to edit the objects that they create.

Project - Uppercut: A full stack Ruby Rails Application utilizing RESTful routes with full CRUD functionality which uses embedded ruby html pages for views. This includes nested models as well with full CRUD functionality.

Project - Flashcards: A web application using HTML/ CSS, JavaScript and jQuery.

WORK EXPERIENCE

C.R. Daniels, Ellicott City, MD

Contract Sales Manager

- Increased sales by over 30% by following up with fabric and coal bag wholesale inquiries.
- Created strong business continuity by processing over 30 purchase orders daily using SAP.
- Awarded company new customers by processing RFQs daily, while communicating with purchasing and engineering departments as well as the customer.

Hennes and Mauritz, Washington, DC

December 2014 – August 2015

October 2015 - June 2016

Flagship Visual Merchandiser

Page 1 of 2

- Increased district's bottom line by providing support to the management and maintenance team.
- Improved product categories through marketing materials and display techniques which resulted in an increase in overall sales.
- Analyzed weekly business reports to create purposeful and effective merchandising.

RW Academy/Columbia Modeling & Acting Academy, Columbia, MD July 2008 – December 2014 Project Coordinator/ Administrative Assistant

- Developed a strong working relationship with YMCA which resulted in creating a new stream of revenue for the company.
- Formed a healthy rapport with current and potential clients by following up regularly and by creating Microsoft Excel documents (rudimentary databases) to organize student enrollment.

Macy's, Annapolis, MD

April 2014 - August 2015

Visual Merchandiser

- Fostered stronger business relationships between brands such as Ralph Lauren, Marc Jacobs, Michael Kors, and Macy's, by successfully interpreting and executing home office directives, allowing our visual displays to fall in line with those brands' original vision.
- Increased sales in all departments by managing business initiatives and timelines and by prioritizing tasks with the management team.
- Expertly executed the installation and hands-on development of interior/window displays

Story House Productions, Washington, DC

May 2012 – September 2012

Lead Media Buyer Intern

- Saved the company more than 50% of projected costs by negotiating with news stations in purchasing stock footage and by contacting smaller stations in lower populated areas.
- Managed team of interns by delegating tasks and creating a Shot Sheet for the pre-production project Paranatural.

Neiman Marcus Last Call, Hanover, MD

July 2011 – March 2012

Merchandising Sales Associate

- Developed a list of top-selling products and brands using local market trends to present to buyers, resulting in the Hanover store location being awarded and recognized for Top-Sales in the Mid-Atlantic Region.
- Consistently named the top weekly and monthly sales associate.

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Washington, DC

Fall 2016

Web Development Immersive, Full Stack

University of Maryland Eastern Shore, Princess Anne, MD

Spring 2011

Bachelors of Science degree, Human Ecology, Cum Laude

Minor, Business Administration

Fashion Institute of Technology, New York, NY

Spring 2010

Associates of Applied Science degree, Advertising, Marketing and Communications

American Institute for Foreign Study, London, England International Retail and Historic Culture of London

Summer 2009

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Dirty Girl Mud Run, Clarksburg, MD Baltimore Running Festival, Baltimore, MD September 2014

September 2014